Nature and Mission of MFSS in a Business Environment
Welcome to this session on Managing for Six Sigma.
This is a very interesting topic because it ties directly with DFSS and PFSS.
In fact, like three overlapping circles,
we have MFSS. And we’ll zoom in here on this.
Managing for Six Sigma. We have over here PFSS, Processing for Six Sigma.
And Design for Six Sigma.
You see, it's Managing for Six Sigma
that creates a linkage between PFSS and DFSS.
It's the bonding agent that brings the two together.
That oversees the two
Remember, management is the judicious use of control for the attainment of an end.
So, management uses control toward the attainment of an end. Six Sigma.
Through the means of Processing for Six Sigma and Designing for Six Sigma.
So, what do we mean when we say, Managing for Six Sigma?
What we're really talking about there, is the whole experience of how to
deploy Six Sigma. How to deploy resources.
How to deploy people.
How to deploy money, knowledge.
And then, and that's of course at the global level.
As we move down toward the local level,
we start to be concerned with implementation.
How do we implement Six Sigma?
And finally, at the activity level,
we start to look at how do we apply Six Sigma?
Now, MFSS is about the
characterization and optimization
of the processes necessary to deploy, implement, and apply
Processing for Six Sigma, tools and concepts,
and Design for Six Sigma, tools and concepts.
So in other words, it's kinda like how do we get the energy to the electric motor?
Managing for Six Sigma is about distribution of that energy
to make these two things happen. That's what it's all about.
That is the essence of Managing for Six Sigma.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.